[
    {   
        "subject_id" : "c",
        "subject" : "C Programming",
        "questions" : [
            {   
                "q_number" : "0",
                "question" : "In which numbering system can the binary number 1011011111000101 be easily converted to?",
                "options" : [
                    "Decimal system",
                    "Hexadecimal system",
                    "Ocatal system",
                    "None of these"
                ],
                "answer" : 1
            },
            {   
                "q_number" : "1",
                "question" : "Which bitwise operator is suitable for turning off a particular bit in a number",
                "options" : [
                    "&& operator",
                    "& operator",
                    "|| operator",
                    "! operator"
                ],
                "answer" : 1
            },
            {   
                "q_number" : "2",
                "question" : "Which of the following special symbol allowed in a variable name",
                "options" : [
                    "* (asterisk)",
                    "| (pipeline)",
                    "- (hyphen)",
                    "_ (underscore)"
                ],
                "answer" : 3
            },
            {   
                "q_number" : "3",
                "question" : "\"An array of three pointers to chars\"",
                "options" : [
                    "char *ptr[3]();",
                    "char *ptr[3];",
                    "char (*ptr[3])();",
                    "char **ptr[3];"
                ],
                "answer" : 1
            },
            {   
                "q_number" : "4",
                "question" : "The library function used to find the last occurrence of a character in a string is",
                "options" : [
                    "strnstr()",
                    "laststr()",
                    "strrchr()",
                    "strstr()"
                ],
                "answer" : 3
            }
        ]
    },
    {   
        "subject_id" : "java",
        "subject" : "Java Programming (Object Oriented Programming)",
        "questions" : [
            {   
                "q_number" : "0",
                "question" : "Which one of these lists contains only Java programming language keywords?",
                "options" : [
                    "class, if, void, long, Int, continue",
                    "goto, instanceof, native, finally, default, throws",
                    "try, virtual, throw, final, volatile, transient",
                    "strictfp, constant, super, implements, do"
                ],
                "answer" : 1
            },
            {   
                "q_number" : "1",
                "question" : "You want subclasses in any package to have access to members of a superclass. Which is the most restrictive access that accomplishes this objective?",
                "options" : [
                    "public",
                    "private",
                    "protected",
                    "transient"
                ],
                "answer" : 2
            },
            {   
                "q_number" : "2",
                "question" : "Which class does not override the equals() and hashCode() methods, inheriting them directly from class Object?",
                "options" : [
                    "java.lang.String",
                    "java.lang.Double",
                    "java.lang.StringBuffer",
                    "java.lang.Character"
                ],
                "answer" : 2
            },
            {   
                "q_number" : "3",
                "question" : "Which interface does java.util.Hashtable implement?",
                "options" : [
                    "Java.util.Map",
                    "Java.util.List",
                    "Java.util.HashTable",
                    "Java.util.Collection"
                ],
                "answer" : 0
            },
            {   
                "q_number" : "4",
                "question" : "Which class does not override the equals() and hashCode() methods, inheriting them directly from class Object?",
                "options" : [
                    "java.lang.String",
                    "java.lang.Double",
                    "java.lang.StringBuffer",
                    "java.lang.Character"
                ],
                "answer" : 2
            }
        ]
    }
]